Hello everyone and welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
today we're celebrating a
very important and very
special American holiday.
That's right, today we are celebrating
and talking about Thanksgiving,
a very, as you say, traditional and
big holiday in the United States.
That's right, so this year it's on
November 25th. It's always on a Thursday.
Let's check out our dialogue to hear
about what happens at this special dinner
and why this is a holiday and then we'll
be back to talk about it in just a moment.
So, what are you doing for Thanksgiving?
Not much, really. It's more
of an American tradition.
So back home, we
don't really celebrate it.
In fact, I'm not even sure of
what exactly is being celebrated.
Well, you know, it's a
time to get together with
all of your family and
be thankful for everything.
Yeah, but how did this holiday come to be?
Well, the first settlers of
Massachusetts arrived there
because of religious persecution
from England and King James.
Once in the New World, they
befriended a native named Squanto
who taught them how to harvest
food from the areas such as corn.
And then what happened?
Well, they had enough harvest for the next winter
and in celebration, they decided to have a big
feast with the natives, giving thanks to the land
and everyone for their food, health and new lives.
Interesting. I am amazed how big
and delicious Thanksgiving dinners are.
Come to my house for
Thanksgiving. We're having turkey,
pumpkin pie, mashed potatoes
with gravy and lots of stuffing.
Come me in!
Alright, we're back. So a
very interesting holiday.
We learned a little bit about why
it celebrated how it came to be.
So let's take a look at some of those
words now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
The first word we have for you guys
today on language takeaway is settler.
Now, a settler is a person.
What kind of a person is a settler?
Basically, it's a person
that goes to a place
to settle down there
or to settle there.
And that basically means to live
there, to stay there permanently.
Alright, but the idea
with a settler is that
he or she will start
to build something.
Build a house, build a city, build a town.
That's right.
So settler's go to places where
there aren't very many people.
That's right.
Kind of hard to be a settler now.
But yeah, back then obviously
there were so many places that were
undiscovered or didn't have
people and they would settle there.
And the place where they went in the
United States is called Massachusetts.
Massachusetts. Now, this is a very
long, very hard to pronounce the word.
And I believe it comes from a local
Indian language, but Massachusetts,
if you break it down,
Massachusetts, is a state.
And you might have heard of the biggest
city in Massachusetts, which is Boston.
So Boston, Massachusetts.
But this is where the settlers first
came when they came to America.
That's right.
So I think if you go to Boston,
it has kind of this atmosphere
of the settlers and how
this old little touch to it.
How it used to be, right?
There is an old field to Boston
because unlike most places in
America, Boston has been a city
for over 400 years, almost 500 years.
So it's much different from
places like California or Texas.
That's right.
Okay.
So the settlers arrived to
Massachusetts and they went there
because of religious persecution
from England and King James.
Okay. So the key here is persecution.
This is something that
you do to someone else or
this is something a government
does to someone else.
Basically to persecute someone
is to limit them or to attack
them or to prevent them from
doing things that they want to do.
That's right.
So basically that is
the reason why they left
England because the
king was persecuting them.
They didn't let them be
have their own religion.
Right.
They had this religion and the
king did not approve of the religion.
And they felt like people were
critical of them or attacking
them or preventing them
from practicing this religion.
And so their religious
persecution in England
pushed them to this
place in New World.
So that's our next word, right?
That's right.
The New World.
And this is what
they used to call the
continent of the United
States or North America.
They used to call it the New World.
So New World, Old World.
So if we think of Europe as being
the Old World, America like you're
saying, Latin America, North America,
these are part of the New World.
So it's almost like they had
never been discovered before.
Right.
So yeah, basically everyone was
concentrated in Europe at that time.
And then when they went to the
West, they went to the New World.
And obviously when they
arrived, it wasn't empty.
They had people there and we say
that they are the natives of that land.
Okay.
So a native of someplace is someone
who comes from there originally.
All right.
So if I came to America
in 1500, there were
native American Indians
who were living there.
And so they're the natives of this place.
Natives.
Now can you use that nowadays?
Can you say I am a native of Italy?
I'm a native of Italy.
I'm a native of Chicago.
Yes, you can.
It's a little bit, you
know, it's a little
bit less common than
saying I'm from Chicago.
I'm from Italy, but it's also correct.
Okay.
But in this case,
we're talking about the
natives as the people
who were already there.
Yes.
Native American.
Like Squanto.
That's the name of that Native
American Indian who was there.
And this native named
Squanto taught them how
to harvest food from
the area such as corn.
So this is the interesting
part of the story.
Because basically these
two groups worked together,
you have Native American
Indians and settlers.
And they worked together to
make a meal and to survive basically.
And to harvest food, to harvest
the key here is that it's a verb.
It's something you do to
crops, like corn or potatoes.
And you take them out from
the field and you bring them home.
Right.
So in this case, the corn
is growing out of the land.
And if you go out and cut it down
and take it, you are harvesting corn.
You are collecting it.
Collecting it.
Exactly.
And so they harvest the food
and they have a very big meal.
So we do want to talk
about the special meal
here that features all
of this harvested food.
Let's take a look at some of those
words in language takeaway part two.
All right.
So talking about the foods.
Now obviously, the tradition is
that you have this big meal together.
And the one thing that is, I think, a
given is that you have a big turkey.
That's right.
So a turkey is a bird.
Mm-hmm.
They make very funny sounds, don't they?
Right.
Like gobble, gobble, gobble.
But they're very big.
They run around.
And they have this red part under
their neck and beaks and everything.
So it's a very commonly
eaten food for Thanksgiving.
But people can eat it anytime.
Yeah, this is a weird thing.
I usually don't see turkey too
much if not during Thanksgiving.
Like, I don't see somebody like,
or I restaurant offering turkey.
No, you don't.
But you do see it in delis
like a roast turkey sandwich.
Yes.
Because turkey is very healthy.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So we have turkey.
We also have pumpkin pie.
So pumpkin pie.
Pumpkin pie.
This is a classic.
You've heard of apple pie.
Mm-hmm.
But pumpkin pie is a baked dessert
that is filled with some pumpkin filling.
Mm-hmm.
So as you know, pumpkin or may
know, pumpkin is a big -- It's a gourd.
It's a gourd.
Yeah.
And it's kind of vegetable.
Kind of like a vegetable.
It's big and orange.
And basically, this is -- it's
kind of sweet, right, the inside.
It is.
It's a little bit sweet.
It's big orange and brown.
Like you say.
People often start to harvest them
around October -- October, I'd say.
Some people like to eat the seeds.
But you can also scoop out with your spoon.
You can take out some of
the meat, some of the filling.
The filling.
And that's what we use
to create this pumpkin pie.
Very good.
So pumpkin pie, delicious food.
Now, we also have a typical
mashed potatoes with gravy.
All right.
I love mashed potatoes.
Mashed means to squish or
to break down or to push down.
And so mashed potatoes,
you have a normal potato.
And you mix up all the potatoes together.
So it's kind of like soft and creamy.
Yeah, it almost becomes like a paste
or almost like, let's say, like, ice cream.
But not cold.
Not cold.
They're not sweet.
But yeah, that's the consistency.
That's what it feels like.
And so when we eat
potatoes like this in
America, we often like
to eat it with a sauce.
And the sauce that we eat with
mashed potatoes is called gravy.
Gravy.
And now gravy is usually made out of what?
Gravy is made from -- well, you
can make different kinds of gravy,
but the way that we make it at my house
is we take all of the juice from the turkey
because when you bake a turkey in the
oven, some -- on the bottom of the pan,
you'll get some liquid,
some water, some fat.
And you use that to make a gravy.
Gravy.
So it's brown and it's
very salty and delicious.
Awesome.
Sounds delicious.
And to end things, we have stuffing.
Now, this stuffing goes
inside the turkey, right?
But then you take it out.
That's right.
So stuffing -- we talk
about stuffing in general as
being something that you
put inside something else.
So if I have a stuffed animal, he
has some cotton inside, or whatever.
But if you have a turkey, you take out
all of the organs, the heart, the liver.
You take those parts out
because we don't eat those.
And you put some bread, onions,
and vegetables inside the turkey to cook.
And then you take it out and you eat it.
So it tastes a bit like turkey
and meat, but it's very delicious.
But you eat it apart, it
kind of like, let's say rice.
It's like a side dish.
Like a side dish.
All right.
It sounds delicious.
And obviously, it's a very big meal.
But very, very common, traditional
holiday in the United States.
It's very fun to celebrate as well.
You get together with family and
you have this nice meal together.
That's right.
It's a wonderful holiday.
And we'll be talking a
bit about it in a second.
But let's just take one more,
listen to today's dialogue.
So what are you doing for Thanksgiving?
Not much, really.
It's more of an American tradition.
So back home, we don't really celebrate it.
In fact, I'm not even sure of
what exactly is being celebrated.
Well, you know, it's a
time to get together with
all of your family and
be thankful for everything.
Yeah, but how did this holiday come to be?
Well, the first settlers of
Massachusetts arrive there
because of religious persecution
from England and King James.
Once in the New World, they
befriended a native named Squanto
who taught them how to harvest
food from the area, such as corn.
And then what happened?
Well, they had enough
harvest for the next winter.
And in celebration, they decided
to have a big feast with the natives,
giving thanks to the land and everyone
for their food, health and new lives.
Interesting.
I am amazed how big and
delicious Thanksgiving dinners are.
Come to my house for Thanksgiving.
We're having turkey, pumpkin pie, mashed
potatoes with gravy and lots of stuffing.
Can we in?
All right, so Thanksgiving
is a national holiday.
Now, you say it's on a Thursday.
It's always on Thursday.
So you get that Thursday off from
school, from work and everything.
You get Thursday and
Friday, so you get two days.
Yeah, it's a four-day weekend.
Oh, nice.
And it's a wonderful
holiday because it's
something that everybody
in America can celebrate.
Because, you know, for
Christmas, for example,
some people don't
celebrate Christmas.
Or you don't really get
holiday time off during a
summer for everyone,
maybe just the schoolchildren.
And so this is actually a nice
holiday because everybody is home.
Right.
So it doesn't have a religious connotation
because you're talking about, you know,
the settlers and how they arrive
there and they survive the harsh winter.
And so, as you say, it's kind of
like a neutral holiday where you just,
it's a good excuse to
get together, have a big
meal and just spend
quality time with the family.
That's right.
You cook all day.
You eat, you watch some football on TV.
You spend some time with your
family and you fall asleep very, very full.
So this is another
very interesting thing is
that usually on TV
because everyone is home.
Everyone is having dinner or
spending time with each other.
They will have a football
game on TV for Thanksgiving.
That's right. So everyone's
sitting around eating
dinner and then there's a
football game on the TV.
Yeah.
So that kind of, that's kind
of bad for the football players.
I have to be playing on things.
Yeah, but they get all hungry.
You know, they're on the field and
they get to go home and eat a big meal.
And have a big meal.
It's very, very interesting.
We'll put some pictures of the food
that's commonly served on this holiday.
And it would be interesting
to know if I know a lot of
our listeners are not originally
from the United States.
So if you are there, tell us if
you've celebrated it or have you seen
it or will you celebrate it or any
story that you can share with us?
That's right.
We are very excited to hear this from you.
And we wish you all a
very happy Thanksgiving.
Visit our site,
www.EnglishPod.com to tell us more.
All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.